Guide to the Office of the Dean, Washington Square College and Washington Square and University College of Arts and Science 1929-1984 (Bulk 1951-1980) RG.19
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of the Dean of Washington Square College
1929-1984
1951-1980
New York University Archives
New York University. College of Arts and Science
RG.19
26 Linear Feet
The Office of the Dean of Washington Square College and Washington Square and University College of Arts and Science is the administrative head of the College and is responsible for facilitating interactions between the administration and the students.
Provenance
The records of the Dean's Office of WSC and WSUC of Arts and Science that comprise Series I were acquired by the New York University Archives on August 1, 1979, when they were transferred by the Assistant to the Dean, Eliana Covacich. The records of Series II were most likely transferred to the Archives in 1981 by then-Dean Jill N. Claster.
Historical/Biographical Note
Beginning in 1947 and ending in 1962, Thomas Clark Pollock served as Dean of Washington Square College. William Earl Buckler succeeded Pollock in 1962 and remained in that position until 1969. In that year, Richard Bayly Winder became Dean of Washington Square College; he presided until 1971. Phillip Mayerson, who had served as Vice Dean of Washington Square College from 1969 to 1971, became the Acting Dean from 1971 to 1973. In 1973 he became Dean of Washington Square and University College (formed when the University College of Arts and Science merged with the Washington Square College following the sale of the University Heights campus). Mayerson served in that capacity until 1978.
The Dean of Washington Square College served a variety of functions within the University's administration, including oversight of the development of curricula in various departments and serving as a liaison between administration and students. These functions and others are reflected within the collection.
Under the administrations of Buckler and Winder, the major purpose of the Dean's office involved helping Washington Square College live up to its potential as an undergraduate college in a large and complex University located in an equally large and complex city.
Under Mayerson, the Dean's office broadened its outlook. He added fundraising as a major function of his office, in addition to attracting and holding students. Mayerson did everything in his power to bring larger enrollment numbers into Washington Square College. He concentrated on personalizing the admissions process, helping the students to mix more with the faculty, cutting red tape in dealing with the problems of individual students, and created a closer relationship between his office and that of the Director of Admissions. These initiatives are well documented in this collection.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of materials relating to the administrative functions of the Dean from 1929 to 1984, bulk dates 1951 to 1980, mainly correspondence, financial records, minutes, printed material, publications, reports, and subject files. There is a great deal of information about the Sunrise Semester in particular.
The collection consists of 52 Paige boxes that highlight the administrative activities undertaken by the Office of the Dean of Washington Square College. Issues such as the early admissions program, Sunrise Semester, and the merger of Washington Square and University College are elucidated in the collection.
Arrangement
The collection had previously been processed in individual parts and has been intellectually combined for the purposes of this finding aid. As such, the arrangement of folders varies between alphabetical and topical.
The files are grouped into two series.
Series I: Washington Square Dean's General Files
Series II: Additional Dean's Files
Separated Material
Photographs have been integrated into the Photo Collection under the title "Early Admissions."
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
This collection is in off-site storage.
Universities and Colleges -- Administration; Photographs.; Press releases.; Reports.; Clippings (information artifacts); Minutes (administrative records); Curriculum planning.; Universities and colleges |x Admission.; Correspondence.; Buckler, William Earl, 1924-; Pollock, Thomas Clark, 1902-1988; New York University |x History |y 20th century; New York University. College of Arts and Science; Winder, R. Bayly (Richard Bayly), 1920-; Phillip Mayerson; University College of Arts and Pure Science (New York University).
- Series I: Washington Square Dean's Files, 168422
  - General Files, 168954
    - "A" Program, 1967-1969; 169146 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      bar code #: 3 1142 04226617 4
    - AB-DDS, 1973-1975; 169145 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AB-DDS, 1976; 169144 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AB-DDS, 1977-1979; 169143 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Academic Affairs Northeastern Conference, 1974; 169142 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Academic Committee Council, 1966-1967; 169141 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Academic Costumes, 1957-1964; 169140 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Academic Deans, Institute of, 1962-1965; 169139 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Academic Planning Commission, 1976-1977; 169138 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Academic Standards Committee, 1976; 169137 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Actuarial Mathematics, 1961-1962; 169136 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Actuarial Science, 1975; 169135 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Addendum to Mission Statement, undated; 169134 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Addresses and Biography, 1970; 169133 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Ad Hoc Advisement Committee, 1972; 169132 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Admissions-BPA, 1979; 169131 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Admissions-Early, 1974-1978; 169130 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Admission Standards, 1964-1978; 169129 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Admission Statistics, 1978; 169128 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Advanced Placement, 1960-1974; 169127 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Advisement, 1961-1966; 169126 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Advisement, 1966-1977; 169125 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Advisory Committee, 1964-1971; 169124 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Affairs Committee, 1964-1971; 169123 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - African Studies, 1958-1974; 169122 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - All Square Student Congress, 1967-1971; 169121 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Altman, Jack, 1962-1964; 169120 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Altschul, Milton, 1966-1968; 169119 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Alumni Advisory Board, 1972; 169118 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Alumni Association Fundraising, 1974-1976; 169117 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Alumni Association Fundraising Samples and Appeals, 1971-1977; 169116 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Alumni Association Great Teacher's Award, 1970-1979; 169115 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Alumni Association Memos, 1975-1978; 169114 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Alumni Association Officers and Directors, 1979-1980; 169113 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Alumni Association School of Education, 1969; 169112 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Alumni Achievement Awards, 1969-1974; 169111 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Alumni Achievement Awards, 1975-1977; 169110 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Alumni Campaign, 1968-1969; 169109 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04226053 2
    - Alumni Career Day, 1976; 169108 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Alumni Club, 1956-1967; 169107 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Alumni Club, 1967; 169106 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Alumni Club, 1968; 169105 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Alumni Club, 1969-1978; 169104 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Alumni Contributors, 1971-1972; 169103 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Alumni Contributors, 1972; 169102 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Alumni Contributors, 1973; 169101 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Alumni Cultivation, 1972-1974; 169100 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Alumni Dinners, 1969-1972; 169099 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Alumni Federation, 1966-1975; 169098 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Alumni Federation, 1975-1981; 169097 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Alumni Giving, 1976-1979; 169096 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Alumni Letters, 1965-1970; 169095 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Alumni Letters, 1971-1974; 169094 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Alumni Luncheons, 1975-1976; 169093 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Alumni Meritious Service Award, 1966; 169092 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Alumni Reunion, 1974-1976; 169091 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Alumni Survey, 1971; 169090 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Annual Giving, 1968-1972; 169089 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Antiquities at Heights, 1972-1973; 169088 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Anthropology, 1967-1968; 169087 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Anthropology, 1969; 169086 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Anthropology, 1971; 169085 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Anthropology, 1972-1975; 169084 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Application Reports, 1976; 169083 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Applied Science Program, 1974; 169082 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Applied Science Program, 1975; 169081 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Art Collection Committee, 1963; 169080 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04226054 0
    - Associate Dean, 1980-1981; 169079 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Associate Degree in Arts Program, 1963-1968; 169078 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Athletic Committee, 1971-1972; 169077 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Attrition Data on Student Retention, 1976; 169076 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Baltzley, Alexander, 1957; 169075 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Baltzley History Prize, 1958-1968; 169074 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Berstein Hall (Martin), 1966-1967; 169073 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Bicentennial Celebration Plans (United States), 1974; 169072 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Biology, 1967-1972; 169071 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Biology, 1973-1975; 169070 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Biology Gifts, 1972-1975; 169069 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Board of Directors, 1972-1975; 169068 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Brazil, Junior Year in, 1958-1963; 169067 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Brazil, Junior Year in, 1964-1971; 169066 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Budget Problems, 1970-1978; 169065 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Bulletin Blurbs, 1977; 169064 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Caducean Society, 1968; 169063 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Caducean Society, 1969-1970; 169062 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Caducean Society and Contribution, 1923-1978; 169061 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Cambodian Disruption at NYU, 1970; 169060 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Campus Stores, 1963-1971; 169059 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Campus Store Incident, 1967; 169058 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Capitol Campaign, 1967; 169057 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Capitol Program, 1961-1966; 169056 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Cartter, Allan M., 1966-1972; 169055 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Case Brochure, 1977-1978; 169054 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Case Study, 1978; 169053 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Case Studies-Departments, 1978; 169052 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Catholic Center, 1968-1972; 169051 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Cause Program, 1976; 169050 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Celine Manuscripts, 1963-1967; 169049 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Chairs-Arts and Sciences, 1958-1964; 169048 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Chancellor's Office, 1973-1975; 169047 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Charter and Bylaws of NYU, 1955-1977; 169046 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Chemistry, 1967-1971; 169045 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Chemistry, 1972-1975; 169044 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Chemistry Interviews, 1968; 169043 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Chinese, 1964-1966; 169042 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Chorus and Orchestra, 1973; 169041 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Christian Foundation, 1970; 169040 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Classics, 1967-1971; 169039 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04226055 7
    - Classics, 1972-1974; 169038 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Classics, 1974-1978; 169037 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Class of 1961, 1961-1962; 169036 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Class Size, 1965-1968; 169035 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Clements (Congress of Italianists), 1970-1973; 169034 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Coler, Myron, 1969-1975; 169033 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - College of Arts and Sciences, 1978; 169032 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - College Bound, 1967-1968; 169031 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - College Entrance Exam Board, 1972-1973; 169030 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Columbia Pictures Proposal, 1963; 169029 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Columbia University, 1963-1972; 169028 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Combined Program CAS/GBA/BPA, 1973-1974; 169027 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Commencement, 1968-1975; 169026 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Commencement Plans, 1976-1977; 169025 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Commerce, School of, 1967-1972; 169024 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Committees, 1972-1976; 169023 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Common Hour, 1967-1972; 169022 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Communication Arts Group, 1965; 169021 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Communications and Society, 1975; 169020 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Community Relations, 1966-1972; 169019 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Comparative Literature, 1969-1972; 169018 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Comparative Literature, 1973-1975; 169017 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Comparative Literature Spring Conference, 1970-1971; 169016 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Computer-Academic, 1968-1972; 169015 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Computer Program, 1967-1970; 169014 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Computer Science, 1969-1975; 169013 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Computing Facilities, 1965-1975; 169012 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Conference of Facilities, 1971; 169011 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Conferences, Institutes, etc., 1960-1975; 169010 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Conflicts of Interest, 1965-1967; 169009 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Continuing Education, School of, 1966-1975; 169008 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Continuing Education--2 Year Program, 1969-1972; 169007 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Cooper Union Program, 1976-1978; 169006 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Cooper Union Program-Literature/Brochures, 1970-1977; 169005 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Co-operative Arrangemetns with Developing Institutions, 1969-1972; 169004 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Co-operative College Center, 1970-1974; 169003 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Co-operative Education Proposal, 1974; 169002 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Co-operation, Inter-School, 1973; 169001 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - COPES Program, 1967-1969; 169000 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1973; 168999 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Council, Student, 1968-1969; 168998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04226056 5
    - Council, Student, 1970-1976; 168997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Counseling, 1966-1974; 168996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Courant Institution, 1963-1967; 168995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Course Consolidation, 1970-1972; 168994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Course Numbering, 1966-1973; 168993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Creole Foundation, 1963-1964; 168992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Cresap, McCormick and Paget Survey, 1968; 168991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Crippled and Disabled, Institute for, 1963-1965; 168990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Critical Languages Program, 1968-1970; 168989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1974-1975; 168988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Cushman, Robert, 1967-1968; 168987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Cutler, Max, 1967-1968; 168986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Danforth Foundation, 1963-1975; 168985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Danforth Foundation--Literature/Brochures, 1969-1975; 168984 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Da Ponte, Marcia, 1975-1980; 168983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Data Processing Unit, 1968-1969; 168982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Davis, Chee, 1970; 168981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Dean's Advisory Group, 1974-1975; 168980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Dean's Council, 1969-1974; 168979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Education: Commission on Undergraduate Education, 1970-1977; 168978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04226057 3
    - Education: Exxon Education Foundation, 1976; 168977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Education: School of, 1966-1971; 168976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Education: School of, 1968-1973; 168975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Education: Senate Committee on Educational Organizational Policies, 1969; 168974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Educational Legislation, 1969-1974; 168973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Educational Opportunities, 1970-1976; 168972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Educational Policy Committee, 1965-1975; 168971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Educational Support Program, 1973-1974; 168970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Educational Testing Service, 1963-1975; 168969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Emeriti Certification Sample, 1971; 168968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Employee Staff Meetings, 1971; 168967 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Endowed Chairs, 1964-1968; 168966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04225983 1
    - Engineering and Science, School of, 1966-1976; 168965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Engineering: Arts-Engineering Program, 1960-1977; 168964 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - English, Department of, 1967-1975; 168963 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Enrollment, 1973-1974; 168962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Enrollment Statistics, 1967-1974; 168961 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Enrollment Studies Commission, 1974; 168960 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Equal Employment and Opportunties Meeting, 1969-1972; 168959 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Esso Educational Foundation, 1964; 168958 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Ettinger Program, 1963-1967; 168957 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Evaluations: Ad Hoc Committee to Discuss Student Evaluation of Faculty, 1973; 168956 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Evaluations: Commission on Student Evaluation of Faculty, 1971-1973; 168955 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Subseries A: Committees, 168933
    - Academic Standards, Committee on, 1973-1974; 168953 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04225984 9
    - Administrative Management Council, 1962-1975; 168952 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Admissions, Deans' Committee on, 1962-1974; 168951 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Advisement, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1970; 168950 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Advisement, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1971-1972; 168949 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Board of Review, 1967-1973; 168948 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Discipline, Committee on, 1968; 168947 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Faculty (Committees), 169165 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Faculty Welfare Committee, 1972; 168946 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Grades, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1969; 168945 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Nominating Committee, 1968-1970; 168944 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Open Admissions, Conference Committee on, 1969; 168943 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Physical Plant, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1969; 168942 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Physically Handicapped Students, Committee on, 1969; 168941 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Role of the Faculty, Committee to Define the, 1968-1970; 168940 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Scholarship Awards Committee, 1969; 168939 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Scholarship Standards, Committee or., 1968-1970; 168938 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Social Work, Committee on, 1965-1967; 168937 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Steering Committee, 1970-1971; 168936 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Still Committee, 1967-1968; 169147 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Student Committee on Educational Policy, 169166 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Urban Studies, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1969; 168935 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Violence, Ad Hoc Committee to Prevent, 1968-1969; 168934 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Subseries B: Subject Files, 168849
    - Admissions Advertising, 1976; 168932 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Admissions: Annual Reports, 1969-1971; 168931 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Admissions: Annual Reports, 1972-1975; 168930 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Admissions, Director of, 1968-1970; 168929 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04225985 6
    - Admissions, Director of, 1971; 168928 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Admissions, Director of, 1972-1976; 168927 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Admissions: Freshmen and Transfer Students, 1971-1974; 168926 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Admissions: Freshmen and Transfer Students, 1975-1977; 168925 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Admissions Interviews, 1974-1975; 168924 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Admissions Office Reorganization, 1969-1976; 168923 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Admissions Recruitment, 1971-1975; 168922 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Admissions Recruitment: Alumni, 1972-1976; 168921 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Admissions Recruitment: Outgoing Letters, 1973; 168920 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Admissions Reports (January-June), 1975; 168919 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Admissions Reports (July-December), 1975; 168918 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Admissions Standards, Revision of, 1972-1975; 168917 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Admissions Statistics and Financial Aid Policy, 1971-1976; 168916 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Admissions: Transfer Students: Promotional Material, 1975; 168915 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Transfer Students (Registration Statistics), 169155 (Box 9, Box-folder 16)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1964-1972; 168914 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04225986 4
    - American Association of University Professors: Collective Bargaining, 1971; 168913 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - An Analysis of Students Who Were Accepted But Did Not Attend NYU, 1975; 168912 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Applicants' Receptions, 1971-1975; 168911 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Association of Departments of Foreign Languages, 1970-1972; 168910 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Colegio Mayor, Universitaria de Madrid: Architectural Plans, 1954; 168909 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Community Colleges Automatic Admissions Agreements, 1972-1974; 168908 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Cooperating High School Project, 1972-1976; 168907 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Dean's Meeting (November 22), 1969; 168906 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Early Admissions, 1969-1973; 168905 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Early Admissions, 1974; 168904 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Early Admissions, 1975; 168903 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Early Admissions Advertising, 1972-1973; 168902 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Early Admissions Advertising, 1974-1975; 168901 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Early Admissions: Carnegie Corporation, 1972-1975; 168900 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Early Admissions: Carnegie Corporation: Three Year Proposal-, 1972-1973; 168899 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Early Admissions Poster, 1975; 168898 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Employment Opportunities: Faculty, 1971-1973; 168897 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      bar code #: 3 1142 04225987 2
    - Employment Opportunities: Faculty, 1974; 168896 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Employment Opportunities: Faculty, 1975-1978; 168895 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Employment Opportunities: Staff and Secretarial, 1968-1974; 168894 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Administrative Policy, 1971; 168893 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Club, 1939-1974; 168892 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Faculty Council, 1968; 169156 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Faculty Marshals, 1970-1971; 168891 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Fall Day Freshmen at New York University: A Survey of their Expectations and Experiences, 1975; 168890 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Fellowship and Grant Opportunities, 1973-1975; 168889 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - German Department, 1974; 168888 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Holidays, 1967-1977; 168887 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Lane Cooper Fellowships, 1978; 168886 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Mabel Rabkin Emergency Fund, 1971-1973; 168885 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - New York University Club, 1972-1978; 168884 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Physical Plant, 1976-1979; 168883 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Print Shop, 1972-1978; 168882 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Promotional Materials, 1971-1974; 168881 (Box 11, Folder 18)